<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[My pc, my cats and me]]></title><description><![CDATA[Blog about my journey learning things and surviving life in general]]></description><link>https://mairandomness.github.io/randomblog</link><image><url>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/mairandomness/randomblog/gh-pages/images/pcandcatsdark.jpg</url><title>My pc, my cats and me</title><link>https://mairandomness.github.io/randomblog</link></image><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Jul 2018 23:22:49 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mairandomness.github.io/randomblog/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[My thoughts on 42, the last 4 months and what I'm looking forward to :)]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div id="preamble">
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I think it&#8217;s been around four months since I last posted. I have been postponing it since around September, I think? Now my memories of the whole experience at 42 Silicon Valley are not fresh at all&#8230;&#8203; But I still want to keep tabs on the things I have been doing and want to do, as well as my feelings in general.  Which is pretty much the whole reason I started this blog for.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_so_what_have_i_done_these_past_months">So, what have I done these past months?</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Looking at things from this perspective might make it seem like very few things&#8230;&#8203; But I can live with that.</p>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_42_silicon_valley">42 Silicon Valley</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Ok, so from August until the start of September I was in 42 Silicon Valley, doing the piscine. A month of A LOT of C coding, usually around 13 hours daily for me personally. <br>
It was a very interesting experience, and I was waaaay more social than I would have anticipated. I have a bunch o peeves that remained around the way some things work there, as well as some details around the way the experience is engineered&#8230;&#8203;
One of the things I was somewhat vocal about was the motto "born to code" which is used by people to justify why minorities in tech are minorities, they were just not "born to do it" and while I get that was not what they meant at all&#8230;&#8203; It still made VERY wary of how many microaggressions I&#8217;d have to deal with.  Since they have updated the website and the twitter handle and I think the phrase is gone, yay!</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Another thing that had me on my toes was the non-existent code of conduct, which sounded really bad. I know a lot of people that refuse to talk or attend conferences that don&#8217;t have them properly set up. Why would I go to a place for a whole month that doesn&#8217;t worry about that?<br>
I think 42 is walking in a good direction overall. A code of conduct was made and it&#8217;s one of the mandatory projects for the students (which is ok, I guess), but I would much rather it was available on the website because that&#8217;s where people are more invested in learning about the school (in contrast to the first day of piscine when you also get a huge list of exercises to do, and will probably not read the code of conduct/harassment policy pdf).</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>That said, the actual program has some interesting premises, it goes in a completely different direction than boot camps for instance. The month in the piscine is mostly spent programming functions in C that already exist, so you actually know how to build basically everything you work with (except for malloc, free, write and sizeof, which is fairly reasonable since the program gets to them eventually). The opposition with boot camps lies in not wanting you to join the workforce as soon as possible, it&#8217;s building knowledge from the ground up from an actual low-level language like C, which is pretty interesting if you have the time to spare.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>It&#8217;s also a peer-learning institution and because of that, a lot of the learning experience is what you make of it, but with the pace of the piscine, for instance, I just wasn&#8217;t able to get theoretically in-depth as I&#8217;d have liked around pointers and such. That might be the kind of thing that you may miss if you come from an Academic background or even un-school background. After the piscine, the course is a lot more self-paced from what I heard, so that may not be that big of a problem, but I still found it to be annoying while I was there.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Passing the piscine doesn&#8217;t seem to have anything to do with the grades you get during it. But there are grades and the grading system is boolean and VERY FRUSTRATING (probably on purpose), especially when the schedule is that tight and most people are to some degree of sleep deprived. I got zeroes for forgetting to print a new line in huge programs or for forgetting to check if my program matched the linter (ohhh, the linter&#8230;&#8203; ) and I felt awful, it&#8217;s the kind of thing that can eat away at your personal confidence (again, especially if you are somewhat sleep deprived). My guess is that the program WANTS people to "fail" to normalize "failure" and to force people to be more throughout and also to weed out people that can&#8217;t deal with the idea of "failing" because that&#8217;s hardly a good mindset to have as a learner. But it still felt disproportionally punitive at times :&lt;</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>All in all, I got in. But have decided not to attend, at least not for now, my mind might change on that one. But I don&#8217;t live all too well with not working and attending 42 would mean not working for a while and also moving with spouse and all to do some not working in Paris or the Silicon Valley, both places that are way more expensive than where I live right now, on my spouse&#8217;s account :/ to have an educational experience that I&#8217;m not sure I WANT to live.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_if_not_42_what_now">If not 42, what now?</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>So after I left 42 I remained around the bay area, SF/Oakland for around a month with my spouse until StrangeLoop came by. It was under a months time, so partner got to work on site, we got to eat a bunch of nice things and visit some cool places. So, my partner works at NoRedInk which is basically the home company of the Elm language. Since I was around I decided to try and do <a href="https://www.gitbook.com/book/raorao/elmbridge-curriculum/details">Elm-bridge</a> even though I don&#8217;t feel that much joy will come from me trying to work with front-end. The amount of pain that writing the view files brought me might have confirmed that hypothesis all too well, lol. That said, it&#8217;s a very nicely made curriculum and I would definitely recommend it to beginners that want to dive into how elm works or to anyone that gets joy from building things and watching them work!</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>So, right now I&#8217;m studying Data Science at <a href="https://www.dataquest.io">DataQuest</a>and I will say that pandas are awesome O-O, in an almost scary way. I almost fear the amount of power I could get after mastering a set of tools like that.
I just came out of a C learning experience, I already thought that Python lists were a very cool and complex data structure and then, BOOM, DataFrames!!! Ok, I think this is more than long enough, just going to register a couple of to-dos and wrap this up :D.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Oh, before that!
I did a productivity journal, just listing things that I want to accomplish/accomplished everyday and it is the NICEST thing if you tend to feel a bit useless or have trouble with how you feel about your productivity. It&#8217;s great having a bunch of lines proving to you that you, in fact, did something with your time.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_stuff_on_my_to_do_list">Stuff on my to-do list</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Apply to <a href="https://www.recurse.com/">The Recurse Center</a>'s April&#8217;s batch, I need to start working on my application stuff :&gt;</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Read <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Cracking-Coding-Interview-Programming-Questions/dp/0984782850/">Cracking the Coding Interview</a>, I mean&#8230;&#8203; I want to get a job next year and reading a book is not the kind of activity I want to dedicate my hypothetical time on The Recurse Center, even though is a very helpful and practical book  ¯_(ツ)_/¯</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Watch the computation series from <a href="https://www.destroyallsoftware.com/screencasts">Destroy All Software</a>, because it seems interesting and fun, really.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Finish Peter Norvig&#8217;s Udacity <a href="https://br.udacity.com/course/design-of-computer-programs&#8212;&#8203;cs212">course</a> on design of computer programs</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Maybe do some <a href="https://cryptopals.com/">Cryptopals</a> stuff? It sounds so interesting!!</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Play Assembly puzzle games!!  <a href="http://www.zachtronics.com/shenzhen-io/">shezen i/o</a> and <a href="http://www.zachtronics.com/tis-100/">TIS-100</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>I&#8217;m also looking forward to December and the <a href="https://adventofcode.com/">advent of code challenge</a>, it might be too much for me to take on by myself but it sounds like a potentially amazing learning experience if I can pair with my partner on it :3</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></description><link>https://mairandomness.github.io/randomblog/2017/11/17/My-thoughts-on-42-the-last-4-months-and-what-Im-looking-forward-to.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://mairandomness.github.io/randomblog/2017/11/17/My-thoughts-on-42-the-last-4-months-and-what-Im-looking-forward-to.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[*The very scary phenomenum of things starting to get concrete*]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div id="preamble">
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="https://mairandomness.github.io/randomblog/images/20170711_111304-1.jpg" alt="drawing of me in despair really not wanting to study" width="but deciding to do so anyway">
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>So it&#8217;s been almost two months since my last post. A lot of things happened and I&#8217;ll try to go trough some of them.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I broke my foot on June 18th, have been hopping around since&#8230;&#8203; Hopefully, my doctor will let me put weight on it this Friday</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_about_leaving_work_and_feelings_on_time_management_and_productivity">About leaving work and feelings on time management and productivity</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>After much stress from being on medical leave right before the day I was supposed to quit working and the end of a school term (I did end up working even with a medical leave), now I&#8217;m not working anymore! I do have stuff from the process of leaving work to take care of, but no actual work anymore.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Which leads us to how easy it is to feel bad about my pace in learning and how bad I can be with time management when I&#8217;m anxious and how that becomes an infinite loop of trying to be reasonable and understanding with myself:<br>
"Agh, if I was feeling better my productivity would probably be way better, maybe I should take some time to take care of myself, I can do this, It&#8217;s healthy.". Because, well, we know that breaks are healthy and that work really flows when we are feeling good. But the equilibrium with breaks to improve productivity, to feeling like you are just being too lenient with yourself, to feeling like you are just slacking off with a fair excuse is HARD. And I&#8217;m going with feeling here because productivity is a very subjective concept and even more so at a self-paced self-learning experience like this one. And feeling, in this case, is really important, while I was still working, studying was like bonus points that made me really happy, right now I feel that there&#8217;s more weight to it, because it kinda became my "job" now.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Which leads us to the next feeling the escalating anxiousness that&#8217;s brought forth by insecurity that was confirmed by the feeling that my productivity is not meeting my imaginary arbitrary metric of "being enough":<br>
"I DIDN&#8217;T DO ANYTHING!!!! HOW CAN THIS BE??? It&#8217;s been a month and I&#8217;m one-third of the way through Zed&#8217;s book still&#8230;&#8203; I&#8217;m not sure that I can grasp the subtleties of pointers anytime soon :( This was a terrible idea and can I really even become a <strong>real</strong> programmer?? I do know that the Math background helps&#8230;&#8203; But there&#8217;s so much I don&#8217;t know&#8230;&#8203; When will I start feeling that I have context? When will I start to feel that I can really make a job out of this? How long will I stay off work? What kind of strain not working for who knows how long will put in my relationship? Just what is going to happen in my life next year?"</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>And I think it feels great to admit all of this and admit that <strong>I don&#8217;t want to study today</strong> (to reference the drawing only, I actually want to study today, maybe grasp macros a little better?), as long as I&#8217;m still able to move with and through those feelings and still do something, because I know that it will take time to internalize a bunch of these things, but exposure is so important&#8230;&#8203; Keeping at it even if I don&#8217;t really want to, feels good some days and doing absolutely nothing on other days can feel just great. I&#8217;m mostly trying to find where my equilibrium lies. For now, I&#8217;m trying to stick to doing a Pomodoro time management thing with an app and it is so hard to get used to (I&#8217;m finishing this in a break)!</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_on_42_and_traveling_to_california">On 42 and traveling to California</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The date of my travel to attend 42 silicon valley is getting closer (because that&#8217;s the way time works) and I&#8217;m getting a bit anxious about it.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>For starters, it is a collaborative space, but with no particular code of conduct or anything&#8230;&#8203; I worry that a lot of the bad behaviors and prejudices that are common to the tech industry will be present to the point of me not feeling comfortable in that space. I got some red flags on the slack channel, but it&#8217;s hard to say that those behaviors are representative of the community. I don&#8217;t want to feel down without the need, but I really also don&#8217;t want to get my hopes up about how I&#8217;ll feel about the environment.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_on_other_notes">On other notes</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I dislike Zed Shawn increasingly as I go through the book, I guess he can complain as much as he likes, but he definitely could teach something while refraining from attacking people that disagree with him&#8230;&#8203;</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I spied Pointers on C and the book starts with such a hard example followed by really easy exercises that I got baffled by the inconsistency of the first chapter and got a little put off. I&#8217;m not kidding or exaggerating, the first sample code is over 200 lines long and one of the exercises of the chapter is "Hello world!". So I decided to get more context in C before trying to tackle that book.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I got in the <a href="http://witchat.github.io/">Wichat</a> (Woman in tech) slack community and it seems like a great place to be in!</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I feel like I would really like Zulip from the Recurse center as well, but for that, I still need to go to the recurse center, so&#8230;&#8203; One thing at a time.</p>
</div>
</div>]]></description><link>https://mairandomness.github.io/randomblog/2017/07/11/The-very-scary-phenomenum-of-things-starting-to-get-concrete.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://mairandomness.github.io/randomblog/2017/07/11/The-very-scary-phenomenum-of-things-starting-to-get-concrete.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Establishing a work-flow of sorts]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div id="preamble">
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="https://mairandomness.github.io/randomblog/images/20170520_011223.jpg" alt="my vim commands wall">
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p><em>a picture of part of my newly established Vim command wall</em></p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>My last post was around a month ago, I&#8217;m still working as a teacher and I&#8217;m also quite the procrastinator, so I&#8217;m moving at a somewhat slow pace on this. Which is also fine, I guess (:</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_what_s_happening_right_now">What&#8217;s happening right now?</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Okay, so Jubs (my partner) was in New York for the last two weeks in The Recurse Center&#8217;s never graduate week and brought me some stuff as gifts~<br>
They have been wonderfully supportive of this whole deal, so much, that in fact, they got me:</p>
</div>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Christopher Allen and Julie Moronuki&#8217;s book on Haskell (quite a while ago)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Learn C the Hard Way from Zed Shawn</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Pointers on C from Kenneth Reek</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>an iPad Pro for reading ebooks and stuff (as an early birthday gift :D)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>they also lent me their previous notebook which is a quite powerful 15&#8217;dell which is currently running on Linux</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>That being said, I haven&#8217;t done much this past month apart from today.<br>
I finished 6.00.2x: Introduction to Computational Thinking and Data Science
course from edx which was nice, and I can say that I got SO EXCITED that the last set of lectures was about statistical fallacies that I even took a week of classes with my high school students to go over the same basic concepts with them, because I truly believe that being able to identify when data is being twisted is a fundamental skill, especially in a world in which you can be bombarded with so much information.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Today in specific I was busy deciding on things to learn over the next months.+</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>One of the things I&#8217;m doing is going over Learn C the Hard Way, which seems to be a good introductory book on C even though Zed Shawn can be quite excessive when asserting his beliefs, the book does seem to be good. The weirdest thing about it is that it comes with a DVD and it&#8217;s not even an old edition, it&#8217;s from 2016. It&#8217;s just obsolete media&#8230;&#8203; I don&#8217;t even own a DVD reader anymore and I don&#8217;t even know how many years it has been this way. I&#8217;m probably going to take the DVD to the school I work in and copy the files to a pen drive, or something. The second weirdest thing is probably the recommendation of using flash cards to memorize operators and its meanings.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Since I decided to go over this book and the author specifies very explicitly that one of the best things you can do if you want to be an actual programmer is not use an IDE, one of the first things was deciding which text editor to go with. I had only used a little bit of Sublime Text before, but not nearly enough to have mastered shortcuts, so I decided to go with Vim, on a Linux machine and also use git to save the projects to access them later (Jubs got on my case about my tossing away a lot of the code I write, that I should keep it instead, even if it&#8217;s silly and quick stuff because it can be useful, so I made a repository of random learning stuff on my GitHub). And since I decided to learn all that new stuff, why not go all the way and work with Linux as well?</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_on_being_a_noob_and_deciding_to_use_vim">On being a noob and deciding to use Vim</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>To be fair, I did play some of Vim adventures (a puzzle game that was designed to teach you how the shortcuts in Vim work) last year but forgot most of it. I did know already that Vim is awfully counter-intuitive, but if a tool is that weird and still so widely adopted, there&#8217;s definitely something there despite the annoying learning curve. So if I have to master some text editor, it might as well be the one with the weirdest learning curve, so I don&#8217;t have to try and master it after I have a good workflow going on in some other text editor.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The first thing I did was look around on the internet to get some cheat-sheets ready in a visible location (aka. my wall).</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>After talking about Vim and it&#8217;s peculiarities with my partner, they mentioned that their coworkers created a configuration for it which is called <a href="https://github.com/stoeffelberg/brangelina">Brangelina</a>. Soon enough we discovered that Brangelina is actually a set of configurations for Neovim, and honestly, it looks pretty good and has some pretty nice plugins. I can&#8217;t express how happy I am that Neovim (unlike Vim) accepts cursor inputs &lt;3<br>
but I am a bit afraid that means I&#8217;m not going to work as hard in trying to memorize the shortcuts&#8230;&#8203; Tradeoffs, right?</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_on_lighter_notes">On lighter notes</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I&#8217;m currently reading a book called "Our souls at night" which is about old people and about making bonds at a very old age. It&#8217;s nice.<br>
These past few weeks I did some crafting, crochet and such.<br>
Basically, a beanie with cat ears and a stuffed octopus while watching shows on Netflix and eating junk food, it did my soul very good.</p>
</div>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="https://mairandomness.github.io/randomblog/images/octopus.png" alt="crochet octopus">
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p><em>crochet octopus, I made for my baby half-brother who is 2 months old</em></p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I spent most of my day yesterday messing around with the iPad, which is one of those devices that I never really thought I would ever want (that was before the apple pencil was a thing). I did get a kindle for e-reading at some point in the past, mostly because I wanted to have access to books in English and because I felt that bright screens were somewhat exhausting. One of the problems of devices like the kindle, however, is that if you read pdfs, it is too tiny to read without zooming in and that can be a bit of a pain.<br>
That&#8217;s basically how the idea of getting an iPad got in our lives, and I&#8217;m interpreting the gift as a very, very supportive message towards me studiyng~</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Jubs is a bit on the fence about the idea of attending the ElixirConf, but we are still pretty much set on attending Strange Loop and Papers We Love on the pre-conf day:3</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I will attend the preparatory boot camp (aka piscine) of 42us from August 6th to the beginning of September and I&#8217;m scared shitless of taking that leap of a career path change, but also SO EXCITED.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I&#8217;m unsure of when I&#8217;ll post again. But I will~<br>
See ya soon!</p>
</div>
</div>]]></description><link>https://mairandomness.github.io/randomblog/2017/05/20/Stablishing-a-work-flow-of-sorts.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://mairandomness.github.io/randomblog/2017/05/20/Stablishing-a-work-flow-of-sorts.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[First things first]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div id="preamble">
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="https://mairandomness.github.io/randomblog/images/pcandcats.jpg" alt="my pc my cats and me">
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>It&#8217;s been a while since I last had a blog&#8230;&#8203; And English is not my first language, so I probably should be spellchecking this&#8230;&#8203; But right now I&#8217;m mostly setting up this blog and looking at how it works in general, and maybe thinking about how to make it look cooler&#8230;&#8203; Maybe I can draw something?</p>
</div>
<hr>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_okay_introductions">Okay.. Introductions?</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>My name is Maira Kodama, 27 yo.<br>
Born: May 30th, 1989 around 7 PM local time São Paulo -SP <br>
I&#8217;m not much of an astrology person, but I like a lot of people that are, so I think it&#8217;s nice to have this out here. <br>
My favorite things about my birthday are:<br>
--- it&#8217;s Saint Joan of Arc&#8217;s day which I personally think is pretty ironic, her being a saint and all<br>
--- it&#8217;s Mikhail Bakunin&#8217;s birthday as well</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I&#8217;m a non-binary person, who usually presents as femme (I accept female pronouns, but I like the neutral ones better). I have a Teaching degree in Mathematics from the University of São Paulo and I have been working with education (in a way or another) for the last 10 years.  <br>
Right now, I feel that to continue to be a teacher in traditional schools I&#8217;d suffer too much or become desensitized. I don&#8217;t like any of those options, so I&#8217;m mostly back to studying and trying to understand (as a student) how I feel about less traditional ways of learning, in which I feel like an active agent of my own education, something that never happened before. And this has been amazing so far :)</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I think that feeling competent in your line of work is a great feeling that I really want to have in my life at all times (if possible). I&#8217;m not able to feel like a great teacher.. and worse: I don&#8217;t think that I can become what I consider to be a great teacher right now. So I want to try other things and try to be good in doing them, in the worse case scenario I&#8217;ll become more of a generalist, which is already an amazing accomplishment &lt;3</p>
</div>
<hr>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_so_what_have_i_been_learning">So&#8230;&#8203; What have I been learning?</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Mostly programming related things.<br>
I remember how much fun I had doing programming classes in college, it was frustrating but FUN!<br>
I also remember that at the time the work/life balance of programmers was famous for being awful, so I never really wanted to work with it.<br>
But now&#8230;&#8203; I see so many amazing people working in companies that are really great cultural wise. And there are so many awesome ways to learn new things!</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>.</p>
</div>
<div class="sect3">
<h4 id="_what_i_have_done_so_far">What I have done so far:</h4>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I was never much of a self-driven person and even though I really want to learn new things I&#8217;ve also learned that (for now) structure and deadlines help me accomplish things. I honestly think this is a bad habit that comes with traditional school (even though some people don&#8217;t develop it) and I feel good about trying to deconstruct it without much hurry</p>
</div>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>spent some time learning a <em>little</em> (emphasis on little) bit of javascript, last year I got a scholarship to do Fullstack Academy online, didn&#8217;t go through with it, it was a lot of money and full-time, which would mean quitting my job as a teacher immediately. Beside having mixed feelings about boot camps and how they seem to deliberately make things hard to keep up because allegedly being desperate turns people into better learners.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>an MITx course on introductory programming in python. It was nice, it reminded me from my CS 101 in college, that was in C and it was 10 years ago, didn&#8217;t remember much. I have some prejudice against python and the whole "there should be only one right way of doing things" ordeal, but the syntax is super clean and I have been told that it&#8217;s pretty great for whiteboarding.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>learned a bit on HTML and CSS, bootstrap on freecodecamp and Udacity. I love the way freecodecamp works, don&#8217;t like the exercises too much. But the idea of getting a certificate after you help a non-profit with your newly acquired skills is something that I really like.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect3">
<h4 id="_what_i_am_doing">What I am doing:</h4>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>I&#8217;m midway through the second course of MITx, called Introduction to Computational Thinking and Data Science. It still reminds me of college, and it&#8217;s fun (for me at least)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>started Udacity&#8217;s Design of Computer Programs that is taught by Peter Norvig, his insights on problems are awesome</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>started an Elm introductory course, didn&#8217;t like the course in particular. But I do want to learn Functional programming and I think that Elm is a good start point, some of the knowledge is transferable to Haskell. So I&#8217;ll finish it eventually</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>still going through some things in freecodecamp, never really did any projects</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>decided to keep a blog on this thing.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>got in 42, the piscine sounded <strong>INTENSE</strong> and cool, so I applied. At first, I thought of only attending the piscine. But the idea of doing some of the actual school program is growing on me.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect3">
<h4 id="_what_i_really_want_to_do_from_now">What I REALLY want to do from now:</h4>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>read The Imposter&#8217;s Handbook by Rob Conery</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>read some of  The Good Math by Mark C. Chu-Carroll</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>learn some Lambda Calculus</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>learn some Haskell (?)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>understand monads</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>get a better understanding on the whole dealing with C and memory handling ordeal</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>get better at this self-learning thing. So I can apply to The Recurse Center, which sounds like an awesome place. My husband attended last year and it was an <strong>experience</strong></p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I guess that&#8217;s it for now. I think I&#8217;ll update this eventually, with new wants and in progress things. We&#8217;ll see :3</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></description><link>https://mairandomness.github.io/randomblog/2017/04/14/First-things-first.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://mairandomness.github.io/randomblog/2017/04/14/First-things-first.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category><category><![CDATA[Feelings]]></category><category><![CDATA[Learningtocode]]></category><pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>